Muhammad Usman

Bahria Town, Rawalpindi | info@rapidevgames.com

About Me:

Working in a dynamic organization helps me to acquire new experiences which makes my skills polished and also helps me to acquire other skills. I am very eager and dedicated to learn new things and also adapt to new environments. Solving real life problems with the help of programming and other technology is the thing which I really enjoy.

Professional Experience:

Unity Developer | January 2021 - Present

Developed 2D & 3D shooting, car racing and fighting games also worked on multiplayer functionalities, Ads integration. Build 10+ game for IOS and Google platform. Implemented databases for web games such as Firebase and Playfab.

Junior Unity Developer | June 2019 - Dec 2020

Working in different areas of game development. Such as UI, Player controller, AI, Animation etc.

Intern Unity Developer Program | January 2022 - March 2022

Participated in a 12-week J Unity Developer program that covered from the fundamentals of Programming and Unity to build skills needed to be successful in game development.

IOT Based Smart Agriculture (Final Year Project)

The project was implemented with the help of Android studio (the application front-end) and for the back-end we use firebase.

Education:

Iqra University (CGPA: 3.24) | 2015 - 2019

Bachelors in Computer Sciences

Superior Group of Colleges | 2013 – 2015

Intermediate in Computer Science

Springboard School System | 2013

Matriculation Major Computer Science

Technical Skills:

- Unity 3D.
- Git.
- Android Studio.
- Languages: C#, C++, Java.

Hobbies:

- Gaming (Online and Single Player)
- Anime